[{"id": "58ec242e8dc25ca9e12ef636", "question": "What color is the car that Starsky drives in the TV show \"Starsky & Hutch\"?", "answer": "Red", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338936", "question": "Whose best-selling diary was written by Helen Fielding?", "answer": "Bridget Jones's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b26e", "question": "Architect Walter Gropius founded what famous German art school in Weimar in 1919?", "answer": "The Bauhaus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a060", "question": "Who directed the 1982 movie \"The Thing\"?", "answer": "John Carpenter", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef93a36ce05a3942286e90", "question": "Which pop musician was deported from Japan in the 1980's for possession of marijuana?", "answer": "Paul McCartney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "592eb17cf83302ff91e464a8", "question": "What cartoon by Mike Judge is the 1999 film \"Office Space\" based on?", "answer": "Milton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff51383ff04d658268c92dc", "question": "Which war was ended by the 1763 Treaty of Paris?", "answer": "The signing of the treaty formally ended the Seven Years' War, also known as the French and Indian War.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339331", "question": "What western drama series told the story of Pat Garrett and Billy the Kid?", "answer": "The Tall Man", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6dd", "question": "What is the target area in Olympic fencing?", "answer": "The torso", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdd5e060499cffc60b84233", "question": "What Egyptian monster feasts on the heart of someone unworthy of eternal life?", "answer": "Ammut", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d42", "question": "What actress shaved her head for her role in the movie \"V for Vendetta\"?", "answer": "Natalie Portman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a988", "question": "What city named its airport after John Foster Dulles?", "answer": "Washington, D.C.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af0d", "question": "What nickname was given to General Thomas J. Jackson during the Civil War?", "answer": "\"Stonewall\" Jackson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6018bc84d96d05b23b281656", "question": "Who captured and murdered the Inca Emperor Atahualpa?", "answer": "Francisco Pizarro", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133906c", "question": "Which famous piece of artwork depicts the \"Battle of Hastings\"?", "answer": "Bayeux Tapestry", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fbaefd00738315b1fb74e33", "question": "Which is the longest English word without a vowel?", "answer": "Nymphly", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399fb", "question": "What CBS sitcom aired Monday nights at 9 pm, from 1951 to 1957?", "answer": "I Love Lucy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c6ae877e98cb977789be", "question": "Which small French town holds an annual festival celebrating Mexico?", "answer": "Barcelonnette", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a852", "question": "Approximately, how many feet above the sea level is Machi Picchu located at?", "answer": "8,000", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4d0", "question": "In relation to the Halloween holiday, what is the archaic meaning of the word \"Hallow\"?", "answer": "Saint", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d6f", "question": "What Nirvana and Smashing Pumpkins record produced later became the drummer in Garbage?", "answer": "Butch Vig", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015ffcafe83fe1f2a824c50", "question": "In the film \"Saving Private Ryan,\" who played the role of private Ryan?", "answer": "Ironically Matt Damon was given this role by Spielberg partly due to his lack of fame.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e8a67c89a45431f553a9cd2", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Great Expectations\"?", "answer": "Charles Dickens", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "592eaf82f83302ff91e46493", "question": "Karl Landsteiner won the \"Nobel Prize Physiology or Medicine\" in 1930 for his discovery of what?", "answer": "Blood groups", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5cc", "question": "What cards do you have if you have a \"Big Slick\" in the game \"Texas Hold 'Em\"?", "answer": "An ace and a king of the same suit", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f55", "question": "What James Joyce story collection begins with \"The Sisters\" and ends with \"The Dead\"?", "answer": "Dubliners", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392b4", "question": "Produced by Francis Ford Coppola, what Academy Award-winning film was released in 1974?", "answer": "The Godfather, Part II", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394c3", "question": "On what movie is the TV show \"Alice\" based?", "answer": "Alice Doesn't Live Here Anymore", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59523d2a736d4be723796b3e", "question": "Musician Drake first gained popularity appearing on which teen TV show?", "answer": "Degrassi: The Next Generation", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba63", "question": "How many scoops of raisins go into each box of Kellogg's Raisin Bran?", "answer": "Two", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b8d4ec2b42d4a3561a9efd", "question": "In the comic book series \"Strangers in Paradise\", what is Darcy Parker\u2019s alias?", "answer": "Darcia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fec8c32ec223966ae8f8847", "question": "Complete the quote \"I have to remind myself that some birds aren't meant to be\u2026\" from the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "\"Caged\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133912e", "question": "Princess Aura is a character from which classic American comic strip?", "answer": "Flash Gordon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0ec", "question": "Musophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Mice", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a402", "question": "Which city has the world's largest castle complex?", "answer": "Prague, Czech Republic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601b48d549076251badbeaa7", "question": "Who was the first African-American to travel in space?", "answer": "Guion Bluford -- On the third Challenger mission in 1983, he earned the distinction of being the first African-American in space.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "594d05eb1a1c922dd1ac64a6", "question": "Switzerland and what other country both have square flags?", "answer": "Vatican City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4dd", "question": "What fruit comes in Key and Kaffir variety?", "answer": "Limes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff51c30ff04d658268c9315", "question": "In the 7th chapter of the Gospel of Luke, Jesus raises a young man from the dead in which village?", "answer": "Nain", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339154", "question": "In \"The Saint\" series of books, what is Inspector Teal's full name?", "answer": "Claud Eustace Teal", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398db", "question": "On what TV show did Amanda Blake play the role of saloon/brothel manager Miss Kitty Russell?", "answer": "Gunsmoke", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca60", "question": "What small gland, attached to the brain, exerts a control over growth?", "answer": "Pituitary gland", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a869", "question": "Andorra is landlocked by what two countries?", "answer": "France and Spain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a709", "question": "What is the third largest National Park in the US?", "answer": "Everglades National Park", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a907", "question": "What major river runs through Rome?", "answer": "Tiber", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59774321284458f1d7854425", "question": "Albert Einstein was offered the position of prime minister of what country?", "answer": "Israel", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe65d811f3c0ead6880d61c", "question": "In ancient times, what were professional writers called?", "answer": "Scribes", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dc5", "question": "Who is the wife in Shakespeare's only interracial married couple?", "answer": "Desdemona", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "595642b5803c1f1ebcc4a02d", "question": "A chameleon\u2019s tongue is up to twice the length of its what?", "answer": "Body", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d41", "question": "What was Dutch painter Rembrandt's full name?", "answer": "Rembrandt Harmenszoon van Rijn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58b8ccf594b094db915830a3", "question": "What year was the Academy Award for \u201cBest Animated Feature\u201d added to the list of awards?", "answer": "2002", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59cdb20f65ff7d326b622a70", "question": "What is the study of rocks and their formation called?", "answer": "Petrology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398fe", "question": "What 2005 movie got its title from a slang term for a US Marine?", "answer": "Jarhead", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133894e", "question": "What Paris cathedral's bells were rung by Quasimodo?", "answer": "Notre Dame's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8d4", "question": "In what country would you find the mouths of the river Ganges?", "answer": "Bangladesh", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe76e69eec85e375820b2dd", "question": "Which country is famously shaped like an elephant's head?", "answer": "Thailand", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5989ae49cb8751d53e7d7614", "question": "Who was the Roman Emperor from 275-276?", "answer": "Tacitus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58c89d11011619dd6d415482", "question": "While pretending to be an inner city calculus teacher, what was Eric Cartman\u2019s catch phrase in South Park?", "answer": "How do I reach these keeeds?", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5989ae8fcb8751d53e7d7616", "question": "What was the first commercially successful method of manufacturing artificial gemstones?", "answer": "The Verneuil Process (also known as flame fusion)", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921b", "question": "What instrument did Sting play with the band \"The Police\"?", "answer": "Bass guitar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe65c641f3c0ead6880d614", "question": "Before starting Wendy's, what fast food franchise did Dave Thomas work for?", "answer": "Kentucky Fried Chicken", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a821", "question": "Botany Bay lies off the coast of what country?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b3589855db0d66a186cb54c", "question": "The Republic of Benin shares a border with which other African country to the east?", "answer": "Nigeria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef5f8f6ce05a3942286e44", "question": "What was the original name of the Boston Red Sox?", "answer": "Boston Americans", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe9f6e7ff048f679a45aae0", "question": "The San Andreas Fault is an example of what type of tectonic plate boundary?", "answer": "Transform plate boundary", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa9f", "question": "Tashkent is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Uzbekistan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afea", "question": "The Battle of Bull Run occurred during what war?", "answer": "Civil War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff2581931a458464a93c464", "question": "What is a bonbonni\u00e8re?", "answer": "A fancy box or dish used to hold bonbons.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cdc", "question": "What sci-fi movie featured Michael Rennie and Patricia Neal?", "answer": "The Day the Earth Stood Still", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b23adf68f1a2238a7cb2b3a", "question": "In the novel series, \"A Series of Unfortunate Events\", who was the Baudelaire's sixth guardian?", "answer": "Jerome and Esme Squalor", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3d3", "question": "What major British disaster occurred in Beauvais, France, in 1930?", "answer": "Crash of the R101 airship", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad77", "question": "Who was the first person to fly solo across the Atlantic ocean?", "answer": "Charles Lindbergh", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbbf", "question": "What cut of beef comes from between the neck and the shoulder blade?", "answer": "Chuck", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fede4566ce05a3942286ddc", "question": "In what country did Mia Hamm learn to play soccer?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c00", "question": "What year was actor Jack Nicholson born?", "answer": "1937", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c51f", "question": "Which body joint includes the patella?", "answer": "Knee", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b4e", "question": "Who wrote \"Gulliver's Travels\"?", "answer": "Jonathan Swift", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea3e9eff048f679a45ab5c", "question": "High blood pressure is also known as what?", "answer": "Hypertension", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a127", "question": "Who said \"I always thought losing my virginity was a career move\"?", "answer": "Madonna", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be03", "question": "What usually has cream in its \"New England\" version and tomatoes in its \"Manhattan\" version?", "answer": "Clam chowder", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392d2", "question": "What was Murray Langston better known as to the public?", "answer": "The Unknown Comic", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fb0", "question": "What film company's logo uses a lamp called Luxo, Jr. as the letter I?", "answer": "Pixar's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b68a", "question": "What company introduced the first automatic washing machine at the Louisiana State Fair in 1937?", "answer": "Bendix", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6a4a220565ad31a57c7c0", "question": "What are Rocky and Bullwinkle\u2019s full names?", "answer": "Rocket J. Squirrel and Bullwinkle J. Moose", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fce", "question": "What TV show did \"Private Practice\" spin off from?", "answer": "Grey's Anatomy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a389", "question": "What country is Ibiza a part of?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5c77cd7424f0f7a362efd542", "question": "How man men have walked on the moon as of December 31, 2018?", "answer": "12", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389e8", "question": "What surname for John in \"The Importance of Being Earnest\" did Oscar Wilde take from the seaside town he vacationed at?", "answer": "Worthing", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdf5", "question": "What Clorox \"formula\" was named in honor of its inventor's birthday, April 9?", "answer": "409", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bd3", "question": "According to Greek mythology, what were Jason and the Argonauts searching for?", "answer": "The Golden Fleece", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bca5", "question": "What kind of clay oven is used to make Indian dishes like naan and chicken tikka?", "answer": "The tandoor", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa4023c73aa70ea0b70b08", "question": "From 1964 to 1980, what country was known as Rhodesia?", "answer": "Zimbabwe", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a58a", "question": "The city of Philadelphia is located in which US state?", "answer": "Pennsylvania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f28", "question": "\"The Great White Hope\" is a fictionalized account of what first black heavyweight champ?", "answer": "Jack Johnson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133927f", "question": "In seasons 12 and 13 of the TV show \"Big Brother\", what competitor is associated with \"crybernating\"?", "answer": "Rachel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d31", "question": "What was the original title of the novel \"Pride & Prejudice\"?", "answer": "First Impressions", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffb61c15dad637d903c8830", "question": "Bammy is a traditional Jamaican bread made primarily of what?", "answer": "Cassava flour", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a372", "question": "What is the capital of Iraq?", "answer": "Baghdad", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e3", "question": "Who is the author of the \"Bourne Trilogy\" novel series?", "answer": "Robert Ludlum", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd6a3536c0f9723ab15cb4d", "question": "How long did the Hundred Years war actually last?", "answer": "116 years", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fb08a91cf631c2414a13b61", "question": "What Nashville venue was Taylor Swift playing at when she was discovered?", "answer": "The Bluebird Cafe", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a527", "question": "Whidbey Island is the largest island in which state?", "answer": "Washington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffa42b5c73aa70ea0b70b14", "question": "Fort-de-France is the capital of what country?", "answer": "Martinique", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab20", "question": "Maputo is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "Mozambique", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339442", "question": "Who played the role of Hana in the movie \"The English Patient\"?", "answer": "Juliette Binoche", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ab", "question": "Who does Emma Watson play in the Harry Potter films?", "answer": "Hermione", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aca3", "question": "What name was given to people who made illegal booze during prohibition?", "answer": "Moonshiners", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59f9bbce364247bf200fb8a8", "question": "Lusaka is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "Zambia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "594a622a2ebb971c1417fb8c", "question": "Which French district does Claret come from?", "answer": "Bordeaux", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba24", "question": "How many World Professional Snooker championships did Joe Davis win?", "answer": "15", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3a7", "question": "How many fingerlike projections does an African elephant have at the end of its trunk?", "answer": "Two", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d74", "question": "Gene Siskel owned the iconic white suit from what movie?", "answer": "Saturday Night Fever", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6c8", "question": "What military cemetery is located across the Potomac River from the Lincoln Memorial?", "answer": "Arlington National Cemetery", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a162ac7f01ec323f8491725", "question": "In 1967 what new safety measure and device were introduced to the UK?", "answer": "Blood alcohol level and the breathalyzer", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf65", "question": "What is Wales' national dish called?", "answer": "Cawl", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133899e", "question": "In music, how should a section labeled as \"fortississimo\" be played?", "answer": "Loudest", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59029fe7cad1ec93f27df765", "question": "What country does the cappuccino originate from?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa4e", "question": "What is the capital of Tunisia?", "answer": "Tunis", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7ccad877e98cb97778a29", "question": "What is the capital city of American Samoa, a group of islands in the South Pacific?", "answer": "Pogo pogo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd6661ca5bfecdd737e0865", "question": "Where is Apple Inc. headquartered?", "answer": "Cupertino, California", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a6d", "question": "In what decade were the books of J.R.R. Tolkien's \"Lord of the Rings\" trilogy first published?", "answer": "The 1950s", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff0b885e662d71a53651025", "question": "Which German painter was sometimes court painter to King Henry VIII of England after 1536?", "answer": "Hans Holbein the Younger", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ad9de5ee748bb36357acde5", "question": "Who played Matlock in the muder mystery series of the same name?", "answer": "Andy Griffith", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b473", "question": "What duo first published the \"Michelin Guide\" in 1900?", "answer": "Andre and Edouard Michelin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015de93fe83fe1f2a824b6e", "question": "What was a boarding device used by ancient Roman ships?", "answer": "Corvus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c578", "question": "What nearby galaxy is name for a mythological princess?", "answer": "Andromeda Galaxy", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6cf", "question": "What doctor invented a device called the Mercitron?", "answer": "Dr. Jack Kevorkian", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5feddbe56ce05a3942286d95", "question": "What was the name of the movie that Elvis Presley made his film debut in?", "answer": "\"Love Me Tender\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdc8", "question": "What brand is known as PFK in French-speaking Quebec?", "answer": "KFC", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8f29101dd7bf43be5e810", "question": "What is a group of rhinoceroses called?", "answer": "Crash", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5b4", "question": "What planet has the shortest day, at 10 hours?", "answer": "Jupiter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5f2", "question": "Since 1995 which state has led the U.S. in milk production?", "answer": "California", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8f09201dd7bf43be5e7ff", "question": "What did Toyota originally manufacture?", "answer": "Looms", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6000ed939a72b906b34e3cee", "question": "What is the name of the apparatus used to measure an unknown electrical resistance by balancing two legs of a circuit?", "answer": "The Wheatstone Bridge, named after its inventor, Sir Charles Wheatstone", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b463", "question": "How old was boxer John L. Sullivan when he died in 1918?", "answer": "59", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af13", "question": "What city hosted the Winter Olympics in 1932?", "answer": "Lake Placid", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc7b", "question": "Who has been called the first victim of the \"Madden curse\" due to his abrupt 1999 retirement?", "answer": "Barry Sanders", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f8d", "question": "Who wrote the book \"Fahrenheit 451\"?", "answer": "Ray Bradbury", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339733", "question": "What is Rambo's first name?", "answer": "John", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4a98e361d1b4d384d5d693", "question": "Which major lake is near the Ponderosa Ranch in the TV show \"Bonanza\"?", "answer": "Lake Tahoe", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d47095f8e329de4f877893", "question": "What type of fruit is a Winter Banana?", "answer": "An apple", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef5e4d6ce05a3942286e31", "question": "Which hockey team did Wayne Gretzky play for in the 1980s?", "answer": "Edmonton Oilers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59a1a37712f2a7826b9b8726", "question": "Barbara Gordon is better know as what heroine?", "answer": "Batgirl", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339089", "question": "Who beheaded Medusa?", "answer": "Perseus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339af1", "question": "What sporting competition was the focus of the 2007 film \"Balls of Fury\"?", "answer": "Ping Pong", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b044", "question": "How long did the American Revolutionary War last?", "answer": "8 years", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397e6", "question": "From which US state does Jerry Hall come?", "answer": "Texas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be7b", "question": "What slang term for the stomach is the highest-scoring ailment in the game \"Operation\"?", "answer": "The Breadbasket", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c442", "question": "What flowers do florists often refer to as \"mums\"?", "answer": "Chrysanthemums", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abe3", "question": "What sea borders Tunisia to the north?", "answer": "Mediterranean sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6ff", "question": "Which US state's official song is \"On the Banks of the Wabash, Far Away\"?", "answer": "Indiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58be2d418faf425cf37add7c", "question": "The American rock band, \"The Black Keys\", hails from which US state?", "answer": "Ohio", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaaf", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Argentina?", "answer": "Rufous Hornero", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7bc", "question": "What natural \"Wonder of the World\" lies off the east coast of Australia?", "answer": "The Great Barrier Reef", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c41", "question": "What is Seamus' full name in the TV show \"Family Guy\"?", "answer": "Seamus Lavine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397a9", "question": "What movie sees Elvis Presley sent to the slammer for manslaughter?", "answer": "Jailhouse Rock", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6ab2f20565ad31a57c825", "question": "Who said, \"Books give a soul to the universe, wings to the mind, flight to the imagination, and life to everything\"?", "answer": "Plato", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015fcd3fe83fe1f2a824c45", "question": "Which toy\u2019s original patented name was the \"whirligig\"?", "answer": "Yo-yo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc72", "question": "What year did the Parker Brothers publish the current version of the board game \"Monopoly\"?", "answer": "1935", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338962", "question": "What is the first name of Agatha Christie's sleuth Miss Marple?", "answer": "Jane", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b45e", "question": "Which female gymnast won 3 golds and a silver at the 1972 Summer Olympics?", "answer": "Olga Korbut", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbfd", "question": "The eyewear brand Ray Ban was founded what year?", "answer": "1937", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7cf", "question": "Bucharest is the capital of what country?", "answer": "Romania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339918", "question": "What was the name of the hotel in the 1960 movie \"Psycho\"?", "answer": "Bates Motel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6017373744491cbd7c5a1786", "question": "What is the name of the iron-clad ship that engaged the CSS Virginia during the American Civil War?", "answer": "On March 9, 1862, the CSS Virginia engaged the USS Monitor off Hampton Roads, Virginia in a naval battle that resulted in a draw.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58c8a4c690aac110e416706e", "question": "Which beer was advertised as \"Probably the best beer in the world.\" in the 1970s?", "answer": "Carlsberg", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aab8", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Honduras?", "answer": "Scarlet macaw", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0ef", "question": "Who was appointed the first leader of the Tuskegee Institute in 1881?", "answer": "Booker T. Washington", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b965", "question": "How many sheets of paper are there in a ream?", "answer": "500", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd27", "question": "In Europe, what are measured in \"Paris Points\"?", "answer": "Shoe sizes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6d7", "question": "What is the end opposite the nose called on a snowboard?", "answer": "Tail", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6010ca020775fa611bce67f1", "question": "Where was the first location of White Castle?", "answer": "Wichita, Kansas", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe65f131f3c0ead6880d634", "question": "In ancient Greece, throwing an apple at someone was a declaration of what?", "answer": "Love", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59f9b872364247bf200fb880", "question": "Giovanni Boccaccio's collection of novellas are known as what?", "answer": "The Decameron", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58b372481c3f17ccc40c8e22", "question": "What English party was politician Arthur Hayday associated with?", "answer": "Labour Party", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5aab2e3758d116dab4aecb3b", "question": "How often must one perform a quotidian task?", "answer": "Daily", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d6f", "question": "What classic novel's subtitle is \"The Autobiography of a Horse\"?", "answer": "Black Beauty", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff6684352a821ff76ae8b02", "question": "What is the name of the food that was miraculously provided to the desert-dwelling Israelites of the Old Testament?", "answer": "Manna", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600f71a8a9e54d890926f6e3", "question": "Where is the International Space Hall of Fame?", "answer": "Alamogordo, New Mexico -- It is located within the New Mexico Space Museum", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aee9", "question": "Which royal house consisted of Henry IV, Henry V and Henry VI?", "answer": "House of Lancaster", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc4d", "question": "What was originally Coca-Cola sold as?", "answer": "Patent medicine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6f8", "question": "Which state is home to the Fort Apache Indian Reservation?", "answer": "Arizona", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601b4c0e49076251badbeacc", "question": "Who got married in the very first White House wedding?", "answer": "Dolley Madison\u2019s sister -- Lucy Payne Washington, the sister of First Lady Dolley Madison, married Thomas Todd in 1819.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389c9", "question": "What New York landmark stands in size 879 sandals?", "answer": "The Statue of Liberty", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe9f0deff048f679a45aaa9", "question": "Trypophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Holes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8f81001dd7bf43be5e83e", "question": "Pteromerhanophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Flying", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58c8a72090aac110e4167083", "question": "What tea is used typically used to make a London Fog?", "answer": "Earl Grey tea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b830", "question": "What is the device that measures the number of steps you take when walking or running?", "answer": "Pedometer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff20ff931a458464a93c43a", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Nostromo\"?", "answer": "Robert Conrad", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe775fbeec85e375820b314", "question": "What constellation appears on the Alaskan flag?", "answer": "Ursa Major", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5feccc10ec223966ae8f88a0", "question": "What book did Jesse Eisenberg purchase during rehearsals for \"The Social Network\"?", "answer": "\"C ++ For Dummies\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339893", "question": "What was Lucy and Ricky's last name on the TV series \"I Love Lucy\"?", "answer": "Ricardo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b3dc01dd7bf43be5e7b6", "question": "What city created a new beachfront when it hosted the Olympics?", "answer": "Barcelona", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c004", "question": "What is philately the study of?", "answer": "Stamps", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d9c", "question": "What author created the character of Tom Robinson?", "answer": "Harper Lee", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a71d", "question": "Which US state is nickname the \"Bluegrass State\"?", "answer": "Kentucky", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2c2", "question": "What is a Googol?", "answer": "1 with 100 zeroes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbca", "question": "Who was the first head coach to win three Super Bowls?", "answer": "Chuck Noll", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c5a", "question": "What was the name of the town where all the characters lived in the comic strip \u201cL\u2019il Abner\u201d?", "answer": "Dogpatch", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ca", "question": "What year was the movie \"Aliens\" released?", "answer": "1986", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd23", "question": "At what university was Gatorade invented, in 1965?", "answer": "The University of Florida", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a860", "question": "Belgium's name is derived from what Roman province?", "answer": "Gallia Belgica", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a778", "question": "What former Soviet Republic lies just across the Gulf of Finland from Finland?", "answer": "Estonia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b22d", "question": "Who christened Hawaii \"the Sandwich Islands\" in 1778?", "answer": "Captain Cook", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6014c7ebfbde8045e48466ca", "question": "What Australian marsupial is often mistaken for a monkey?", "answer": "Cuscus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a87c", "question": "In what city would you find the most famous street named \"Yonge Street\"?", "answer": "Toronto", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b31e", "question": "Constance Markievicz, became the first ever what In 1918?", "answer": "British female MP", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe36d7d0ada16518afdc042", "question": "What does \"UL\" in a circle mean, when found on electrical equipment?", "answer": "Underwriters Laboratory", "category": "general"}, {"id": "597de01177980686f722d188", "question": "The word \"Sandwich\" is a reference to which 18th century English aristocrat?", "answer": "John Montagu", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59f9b82c364247bf200fb87c", "question": "For which game was the Steam Workshop service created to allow players to share modifications?", "answer": "Team Fortress 2", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b81d", "question": "What year was the lava lamp launched?", "answer": "1965", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b732", "question": "Cherries jubilee was created and named in honor of what?", "answer": "Victoria's 75th year as queen", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339df2", "question": "What 1990 dance craze gave the Digital Underground their biggest hit?", "answer": "The Humpty Hump", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab54", "question": "What sea does Slovenia have water access to?", "answer": "Adriatic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133add8", "question": "When did the \"Eighty Years War\" end?", "answer": "1648", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133961a", "question": "The \"Sacred Order of the Stonecutters\" was a fictional club in which TV show?", "answer": "The Simpsons", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb68cb5dad637d903c8844", "question": "The unofficial Wei\u00dfwurst\u00e4quator, or \"white sausage equator\", separates Bavaria and the south from the rest of which country?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1c9", "question": "Which film featured the song \"Springtime for Hitler\"?", "answer": "The Producers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339280", "question": "What season 13 competitor in the TV show \"Big Brother\" told Rachel that she rooted for her in season 12?", "answer": "Cassi", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59067c00ff9c0647b50a8069", "question": "What artist received the most Grammy Awards in 2016?", "answer": "Kendrick Lamar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133975c", "question": "Helen Mirren won best actress Oscar, beating out Meryl Streep, for which 2006 movie?", "answer": "The Queen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4a5", "question": "Which country were the 1928 Summer Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Netherlands", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339516", "question": "What was the name of Jasmine's tiger in Disney's \"Aladdin\"?", "answer": "Rajah", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58f564fc33a95c66dc4fe753", "question": "What is the connection between Johnny Logan and Sean Sherrard?", "answer": "They are the same person", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae1d", "question": "Which country experienced a period called the Meiji Restoration?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015eca3fe83fe1f2a824c05", "question": "Which serving president was the first to have his photograph taken inside the White House?", "answer": "James K. Polk", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1fe", "question": "Which country were the 2010 Winter Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a742", "question": "The Arkansas River flows into what river?", "answer": "Mississippi River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b060", "question": "When did the Panama Canal open?", "answer": "1914", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e8029ede59ea584496fe97", "question": "The song \"Hand on Your Heart\" was a hit in 1989 for which singer?", "answer": "Kylie Minogue", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398c3", "question": "What instrument does Rolf play on \"The Muppet Show\"?", "answer": "Piano", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e63afe83fe1f2a824bc9", "question": "Who ultimately succeeded King Alfred the Great as \"King of the Anglo-Saxons\"?", "answer": "Edward the Elder", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb42", "question": "What was Michael Jordan's jersey number for most of his NBA career?", "answer": "23", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf92", "question": "In what game do countries play for the Venice Cup?", "answer": "Contract Bridge", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaf9", "question": "N'Djamena is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "Chad", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339917", "question": "What daytime soap opera takes place in the fictional town of Salem?", "answer": "Days of Our Lives", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "592ead0ef83302ff91e46476", "question": "In which country would you find the city Geneva?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0ff", "question": "In the 1890's, what type of cheese did a California man named David Jacks introduce?", "answer": "Monterey Jack", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5feddaec6ce05a3942286d8a", "question": "Which videogame console did Nintendo release directly prior to the Wii?", "answer": "The GameCube, released in 2001, was the predecessor to the Wii.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392db", "question": "What cartoon character often promised that he would gladly pay you Tuesday for a hamburger today?", "answer": "Wimpy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aa1", "question": "What legendary jazz trumpeter was nicknamed \"Satchmo\"?", "answer": "Louie Armstrong", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a069", "question": "Anna Maria Louisa Italiano changed her name to what?", "answer": "Anne Bancroft", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339410", "question": "What was the maiden name of \"Leave It to Beaver\" TV mom June Cleaver?", "answer": "Bronson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be08", "question": "Which of Santa's reindeer have names that mean \"thunder\" and \"lightning\" in German?", "answer": "Donner and Blitzen", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59071f473745b36be73039ea", "question": "What is the name of Dana and Em's father in the comic book series \"Revival\"?", "answer": "Wayne Cypress", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a65b", "question": "The city of St. Louis is located in which state?", "answer": "Missouri", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b820", "question": "What flavors make up Neopolitan ice cream?", "answer": "Vanilla, chocolate and strawberry", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ad7ebc7b24f84e0b9f9ffe0", "question": "Which drummer led a band called \"The Jazz Messengers\"?", "answer": "Art Blakey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8ea", "question": "What is the most general and highest taxonomy rank of organisms?", "answer": "Domain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb74", "question": "An amendment to the US Constitution must be ratified by what fraction of all the states?", "answer": "75%", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a3c83c4039f3d7859290ffb", "question": "In the TV Show \"Gunsmoke\", who portrayed deputy Chester Goode?", "answer": "Dennis Weaver", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59675fea2b59efe0e9417e9b", "question": "What ball has 32 panels?", "answer": "A soccer ball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59029ea5cad1ec93f27df757", "question": "What style of beer is used to make a \"Black Velvet\" cocktail?", "answer": "Stout", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339060", "question": "How many children did poet Sylvia Plath have?", "answer": "2", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a408", "question": "The English explorer Admiral John Franklin discovered what in the 1840s?", "answer": "The Northwest Passage", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339413", "question": "In the opening scene of the credits for \"The Brady Brunch\", which of the females appears in the upper corner?", "answer": "Marcia", "category": "entertainment"}]